杰森  你来这小巷做什么
What are you doing in an alley, Jason?
芝加哥咋样呀
How's Chicago?
很棒  猜猜发生了什么
Great. So, guess what happened?
你因为举办疯狂派对被逐出宾馆
You were kicked out of the hotel for throwing a crazy party.
当年多美好呀
Those were the days.
不是  他们将余下的德里克·斯道姆系列
No, they moved the rest of the dates
签售时间安排在了婚礼之后
of the Derrick Storm book tour to after the wedding.
你知道这意味着什么
So you know what that means?
我要回家啦
I'm coming home.
好歹表现点喜悦之情呀
Try to contain your excitement.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我是缺乏睡眠  不是缺乏激情
That was lack of sleep, not lack of enthusiasm.
我昨晚忙活我们的"项目"来着
I just -- I was working on our...project.
你出去了  独自一人
You went out? Alone?
你知道有多危险啊
You know how dangerous this is.
我很小心的
Yeah. I was careful.
我没有选择
And I didn't have a choice.
杰森·马科斯回城了
Jason Marks came back to town.
他在12大街被一辆黑色林肯城市接走
He got picked up on 12th Street by a black town car
去进行深夜密会
for a late-night meet.
和谁
With whom?
我不知道  我没跟去
I don't know. I backed off.
看  我没有鲁莽行事吧
See? I was being responsible.
不  叫增援才算不鲁莽
No, being responsible means taking backup.
也许该让莱恩和埃斯波西托
Maybe it's time we brought Ryan and Esposito
也一起来调查了
into the loop on this.
不要  我不能让他们拿工作冒险
No, I'm not putting their careers at risk, too.
有工作  我得走了
Hey, that's work. I have to go.
旅途平安  好吗
Listen, have a safe flight, okay?
我爱你
I love you.
好的  我更爱你
Yeah, well, you better.
距婚礼只有两周
It's two weeks till the wedding,
也来不及归还礼服了
and it's too late to return the tux.
一名清洁工早晨五点左右
A street sweeper found the body
发现了尸体  并报了警
and called it in around 5:00 A.M.
被害人有钱包吗
Did the victim have a wallet?
有  名字叫杰森·马科斯
Yeah. His name is Jason Marks.
根据他钱包里的名片
According to the business card in his wallet,
他在华盛顿区的K街有一家政治顾问公司
he runs a political-consulting firm on K Street in D.C.
没事吧
You okay?
没事  没事
Yeah. Yeah, fine.
公司那边说他来城里干什么了吗
So, did the firm say what he was doing in town?
还没有  我留了个口讯
Oh, no, not yet. I left a message.
还没有回音
Still haven't heard back yet.
他是被枪杀的
So, he was shot?
胸部中两枪
Double tap to the chest.
并且是近距离射击
At close range, too.
推测出死亡时间了吗
Get what time?
我估计是在午夜12点至2点之间
I'm guessing between 12:00 and 2:00 A.M.
这里没有多少血迹
Well, there's not a lot of blood,
他一定是在其他地方遇害
so he must have been killed someplace else.
然后把尸体丢在了这里
Then they brought his body here and dumped it.
莱恩  有目击者吗
Ryan, were there any witnesses --
有人看到有车开走吗
anyone that saw a car driving away?
还没  不过盘查才刚开始
Not yet, but I just started the canvass.
把交通监控调出来
Okay, let's take a look at the traffic cam,
看当时有没有其他人在巷子里
see if we can figure out who else was in this alleyway.
我已经在找了
Actually, I'm already on that.
我把17大街翻了个遍
I've been all up and down 17th street.
没有一个监控  不过我已经在调两个街区内的
There are no cameras, but I'm pulling all traffic video
所有交通监控录像了
in a two-block radius.
这样吧
You know what? Um...
把半径扩大到五个街区
Why don't we extend that to a five-block radius?
五个  平常都是两个啊
Five? We usually only do two.
我知道  就当是直觉吧
Yeah. I -- you know, just call it a hunch.
好吧
All right.
分局见
I'll see you guys at the precinct.
我还有事要处理
I have to go and take care of something.
-可恶  -理查德·卡塞尔  请留言
- Damn. - This is Richard Castle. Leave me a message.
卡塞尔  你还在飞机上吧
Hey, Castle. You're probably still in the air.
落地后直接来分局
Listen, when you land, come straight to the precinct.
出事了
Something's happened.
贝克特
Hey, Beckett.
-你还好吗  -还好
- You good? - Yeah.
杰森·马科斯的公司找到线索了吗
Did you get anything from Jason Marks' office?
我去了  他们根本不知道他回来了
Yeah. They had no idea that he was in town,
连家人也不知道
neither did his family.
不管他回来要做什么
Whatever he was doing here,
绝对是个秘密
he was keeping it on the down-low.
不过我们发现
But we did find out
他住在市中心一家旅馆
that Marks was staying at a hotel in midtown.
正在查他在旅馆期间
We're checking to see whether he had any guests
有无访客和出入电话情况
or made any phone calls while he was there.
我找到的线索比那好多了
I just found something a whole lot hotter than that.
按你说的  我调查了五个街区内的监控
I pulled footage from a five-block radius, like you asked.
你的直觉太准了
Turned out to be a hell of a hunch.
12大街的一个监控拍到了马科斯在一辆林肯里
A camera off 12th caught marks in a town car.
看看是谁开的
Look who's driving.
瓦肯·西蒙斯
Vulcan Simmons.
如果这照片是
If this picture was taken
凌晨1点16在离案发现场5街区处拍的
five blocks from the crime scene at 1:16 a.M.,
说明马科斯很可能是不久后被杀的
it means that Marks was probably killed just a few minutes later.
说不定哪个监控拍拍到了瓦肯开枪
Maybe there's some other video of Vulcan pulling the trigger.
没有  我一直追踪他到15大街
There isn't -- I was able to track him to 15th Street
但是之后就没有监控了
but there's no coverage after that.
瓦肯·西蒙斯这种毒枭
What's a drug lord like Vulcan Simmons
为什么会和特区的政治顾问有瓜葛
doing mixed up with a D.C. political consultant, anyway?
六周  卡塞尔
Six weeks, Castle.
我们追查了瓦肯·西蒙斯六周
Six weeks following Vulcan Simmons,
希望能有些许线索
hoping for a lead.
刚刚找到连接他和布莱肯的关键人物
And when we finally find someone that connects him to Bracken,
这人就死在了小巷里
the guy ends up dead in an alley?
如果杰森·马科斯是瓦肯的赃款和
If Jason Marks is the conduit between Vulcan's drug money
布莱肯议员总统大选的导管
and senator Bracken's presidential campaign,
他们为什么要杀他
why would they kill him?
情况有变
Something's changed.
也许这是布莱肯的防御措施
Maybe Bracken's firewalling himself again --
要在牵扯出自己之前抹杀证据
erasing all of the dots before they connect back to him.
我们得在线索断掉前行动了
We have to move fast before those dots disappear.
不行  我们说好了的  不能冒险
No. We talked about this -- no unnecessary risks.
我绝不要看着谋杀我母亲的凶手
I'm not gonna stand by while my mother's murderer
成为美国总统
becomes president of the United States.
也许不会如此
Maybe you won't have to.
我们把马科斯的死看成了阻碍
We've been looking at Marks' death like it's a setback.
也许这正是我们需要的转机呢
What if it's the breakthrough we need?
什么意思
What do you mean?
瓦肯·西蒙斯成了一桩谋杀案的
Vulcan Simmons just became the prime suspect
头号嫌疑人
in a murder investigation.
你就可以彻查他的过去
You've been given an all-access pass to his life.
只要我们出好牌  你就能定他的罪
We play our cards right, you nail him with this...
他就可能供出布莱肯
He might roll on Bracken.
探长  请来我的办公室
Detective? My office, please.
长官  你不能这样做
No, sir, you can't do this.
你不能让我放弃这个案子
You can't take me off this case.
没人比我更了解瓦肯·西蒙斯
Nobody knows Vulcan Simmons like I do.
也没人像你这样和他有这么深的过节
And no one has a history with him like you do.
他的律师会指责我们公报私仇
His lawyers will spin it as a personal vendetta.
西蒙斯先生正被带来问话
Now, Mr. Simmons is being brought in for questioning,
最好不要让他见到你
and it's best that you're not here when he shows up.
长官  我需要办这个案子
Sir, I need to be a part of this case.
我懂
I know.
但是不行
But you can't be.
休假半天  探长
Take the rest of the day off, detective.
这是命令
That's an order.
这辆车是关键
This car's the key.
如果瓦肯在车上杀掉了马科斯
If that's where Vulcan killed Marks,
我们就能在车上找到足够证据
then we'll find the forensic evidence in it.
除了供出布莱肯  他将别无选择
He'll have no choice but to cut a deal and give up Bracken.
我们很接近了  卡塞尔  我能感觉到
It's just that we're so close, Castle. I can feel it.
但是我们需要找到那辆车
But we need to find that car.
莱恩和埃斯波西托正在全力调查
Ryan and Esposito are all over this.
你也知道的  对吧
You know that, right?
分局来的
It's the precinct.
怎么样了
Hey. How'd it go?
我们得释放瓦肯了
We had to cut Vulcan loose.
什么
What?!
怎么回事
What happened?
他的律师声称照片上的人不是他
His lawyers are claiming that it's not him in that photo.
而且瓦肯也没有任何车辆登记
And since Vulcan doesn't have any vehicles
在他名下  我们没有证据
registered to his name, we can't prove that it is.
莱恩  听着  你得在他销毁
Ryan, listen to me -- you have to seize that town car
一切凶案证据之前找到那辆林肯
before he gets rid of all of the evidence of the murder.
我们会尽力的  但他没有任何记录
Well, we would if we could, but the man has no paper trail.
我们查不到他住在哪里
We can't even figure out where he lives,
更别说他把车藏在哪
let alone where he keeps that car.
得罪了个姑娘  她就永远记恨你
Get a girl's hair wet and they never let it go.
你不会开枪的  探长
You are not going to shoot me, detective.
不会吗
No?
再走一步试试
Then take another step!
我死在这
Me laying dead?
你擅自闯入这里
You here trespassing?
而且你还带着血海深仇
With that big ol' grudge you carry?
你的上司都会怎么想
What are your bosses gonna say to that?
你杀了杰森·马科斯
You killed Jason Marks,
车里的血迹就是证据
and the blood in the car is gonna prove it.
那幸好你有搜查令
Well, then, it's a good thing you have a warrant.
你拿到搜查令了吧  探长
You do have a warrant, don't you, detective?
这真是可惜
Aw. Now, see, that's a shame.
因为现在这个证据
Because now all that evidence
已经是非法取得而不能被采纳
has become fruit of the poisoned tree.
我和我的律师真得谢谢你
My lawyers and I thank you.
谁指使你的
Who do you work for?
这一局你输了  探长
You lost this round, detective.
走吧
Now run along.
没找到答案我是不会走的
Not until I get some answers.
你好
Yeah, hello?
是我埃斯波西托  贝克特和你在一起吗
Yo. It's Espo. Is Beckett with you?
怎么了  发生什么事了
Why? What's going on?
盖茨让她回来查瓦肯·西蒙斯的案子
Well, Gates is putting her back on the Vulcan Simmons investigation.
是吗
She is?
她不是不想让贝克特和他正面交锋吗
I thought she didn't want Beckett going toe-to-toe with him.
这个问题不存在了
That's not gonna be an issue anymore.
瓦肯·西蒙斯被杀了
Vulcan Simmons has been murdered.
今天早上你去哪了
Hey. Where were you this morning?
回头说
Uh...not now.
什么情况
What do we think happened?
有人折磨了他
Someone tortured the man.
根据血流特征
Based on blood patterns,
他半个小时内被枪击中了五次
he was shot five times over a span of a half an hour.
凶手先击中了膝盖  然后是肩膀
So the killer started at the knees, then shoulders,
最后一击致命  穿过了心脏
and finally, a fatal round through the heart.
看上去凶手可能是在审问他
It seems like the shooter may have interrogated him --
折磨他来获取信息
Inflicting pain to get information, perhaps.
法医证据呢
What about forensic evidence?
没有太多可查的  凶手非常小心
Not much to go on -- our killer was careful,
捡走了打出的弹壳
picked up the spent shell casings.
弹道匹配呢
How about ballistics?
要还原子弹不太可能
It doesn't look like I'll be able to recover the bullets.
是因为损坏太严重了吗
Because they're too damaged?
因为它们不见了
Because they're gone.
杀害他的人把子弹从尸体里取出来了
Whoever did this, dug them out of the body.
也就是说  凶手知道
In other words, the killer knew
我们会调查什么于是掩盖了痕迹
what we'd look for and covered their tracks.
你了解瓦肯的一切
You know Vulcan's world.
能想到是谁干的吗
Any idea who might have done this?
不能  长官
No, sir.
有目击者吗
Do we have any witnesses?
目前还没有找到
Not that we've found so far.
但是我们找到了西蒙斯先生开的车
But we did find the car Mr. Simmons was driving,
里面还有血迹  应该是杰森·马科斯的
and there's blood inside -- most likely from Jason Marks.
跟我来
I'll show you.
卡塞尔
Hey, Castle.
有时间吗
Got a sec?
怎么啦
What's up?
我们刚刚盘问了一下
We were just canvassing.
有一个目击者说他们昨晚看到有人在这
We spoke to a witness who said they saw someone here last night.
一个女人偷偷溜了进来
A woman sneaking onto the property.
据目击者描述她高挑  深色头发
Witness described her as "A tall brunette,
长得很好看不像是这附近的人
too good-looking to be in this neighborhood."
是的  我在那
Yes. I was there.
可我没有杀他
But I didn't kill him.
不过我想过
I thought about it, though.
你怎么回事  凯特  我们说好了的
What the hell, Kate? We had a deal.
你为什么没跟我说
Why didn't you tell me?
我知道你不会让我去的
I knew you wouldn't let me go.
我当然不会  这太莽撞了
You're damn right. I wouldn't risk reckless.
我估计到了风险
It was a calculated risk.
我不能让瓦肯逃走
I couldn't let Vulcan slip away.
只是我的速度不够快
Only, I didn't move fast enough.
那昨晚发生了什么
So, what happened last night?
他在阴暗处等着
He was in the shadows. He was waiting.
他好像知道我会去
It's like he knew I was coming.
我们说了几句话
And we had words.
就这样
That's it.
我走的时候他还活着
He was alive when I left.
你没有看到其他人吗
And you didn't see anyone else?
没有  只有他
No. Just him.
凯特  你不能告诉任何人你去过车库
Kate, you absolutely cannot tell anyone you were at that garage.
我知道
I know.
他们是谁
Who are they?
那个走在前面的是多诺万警监
The guy in the front is captain Donovan.
内务部的
He's internal affairs.
盖茨调到这后  就是他接任
He took over after Gates transferred here.
他来这里干什么
What's he doing here?
蕾妮  你好
Lanie? Hey.
凯特  有麻烦了
Kate, we have a problem.
怎么了
What's wrong?
我在瓦肯的尸体里找到一发子弹
I found a bullet in Vulcan's body,
打在在脊柱里
Lodged in his spine
是一颗40毫米的子弹
a .40 caliber.
凶手一定是没看见这颗子弹
Killer must have missed it.
这会有什么麻烦
How is that a problem?
如果弹道测试找到匹配的枪  那么...
If ballistics gets a match, then...
的确找到了匹配的枪
Ballistics did get a match.
射出这颗子弹的手枪登记在你的名下
The bullet came from a pistol that was registered to you.
凯特
Kate...
瓦肯·西蒙斯是被你的枪杀死的
Vulcan Simmons... was killed with your gun.
怎么可能会是你的枪
How could it be from your gun?
你的枪在你这
You have your gun.
那是我的备用枪
That's my backup piece.
我家里的保险柜里有一把40毫米口径的枪
I have a .40 cal in my safe at home.
你被陷害了
You're being set up.
我看了弹道测试报告  马库斯  肯定弄错了
I see what the ballistics report says, Marcus, but it's wrong.
贝克特探长绝对不会做出这种事
Detective Beckett would never do anything like this.
我不是来跟你争论的  维多利亚
This isn't a debate, Victoria.
我们有交情所以我才来给你提个醒
I'm just giving you a heads-up 'cause we have history.
告诉我她在哪
Now, where is she?
看好其它的门
Cover the other doors.
你这是在犯错  马库斯
You're making a mistake, Marcus.
这里另有蹊跷
Something else is going on here.
无所谓  我有命在身
Doesn't matter. I have my orders.
贝克特探长在哪
Where's Detective Beckett?
我不知道
I have no idea.
封锁分局
Lock down the precinct.
一定不能让她离开这栋楼
Make sure she does not leave this building.
我跟你说了  我不知道她去哪了
I'm telling you, I don't know where she went.
你刚才还跟贝克特探长在休息室里
You were just in the break room with Detective Beckett.
她逃走前跟你说什么了
What did she say to you before she fled?
她没有杀瓦肯·西蒙斯
That she didn't kill Vulcan Simmons.
你知道这个女人现在是通缉犯吗
Do you understand this woman is now the target of a manhunt,
还很可能是个杀人犯
that she's most likely a murderer?
我帮不了你
I can't help you.
让他走
I want him gone.
他不该待在这个分局
He has no business in this precinct --
至少在我们调查此案期间
not while we're conducting this investigation.
我想他说得对  卡塞尔先生
I'm afraid he's right, Mr. Castle.
你得离开了
You're gonna have to leave.
很乐意
Gladly.
副队
L.T.
跟我们走一会
Follow us a minute.
快点
Make it fast.
这是怎么回事  卡塞尔
What's this all about, Castle?
伙计们  她不愿把你们牵扯进来
Guys, she wouldn't want you involved.
我们已经牵扯进来了  我们是一家人  兄弟
We're already involved. We're family, bro.
我们知道这不仅仅是瓦肯·西蒙斯的事
We know this is bigger than Vulcan Simmons.
为什么
How?
我们在杰森·马科斯所住酒店的周围排查过
We canvassed around the hotel where Jason Marks was staying.
领班说他跟这个人见过面
The bell captain there said he had a meeting with this man.
眼熟吗
Look familiar?
是的  是史密斯
Yeah. That's Smith.
蒙哥马利警监的朋友  对吧
Captain Montgomery's friend, right?
就是他掌握着布莱肯的资料
The one who kept Beckett safe
从而确保了贝克特的安全
by holding those files on Bracken.
后来被人炸没了
Until they got blown to high heaven.
是的  但是史密斯已经死了  死在医院了
Yeah, but Smith is dead. He died in the hospital.
可能他是想让别人这么以为
Maybe that's just how he wanted it to look.
史密斯的确有能力伪造死亡
Smith did have the resources to fake his own death.
而且这是唯一能让布莱肯不再追杀他的办法
And that is the only way Bracken would stop hunting him.
布莱肯
Bracken?
这事都是因为他吗
Is that what this is all about?
我们认为瓦肯贩毒的钱资助了他的竞选活动
We believe Vulcan's drug money was funding his campaign.
我们想找到他们的联系
We were trying to find a link,
可能我们太接近真相了
but maybe we got too close.
史密斯扮演什么角色
Well, how does Smith fit in?
我不知道
I don't know.
但如果他冒险重新现身
But if he took the risk of showing himself,
那么一定出了很大的事
something big must be going on.
贝克特现在正被
Between the cops and Bracken's guys,
警察和布莱肯的人追捕
Beckett's right in the cross hairs.
我们能做些什么
What can we do?
各位  我们得走了
Guys, we got to go.
我再通知你们
I'll let you know.
-你还好吗  -是的
- You okay? - Yeah.
你被跟踪了吗
Were you followed?
没  没有  我特意换了三辆出租车
No. No, no. I switched cabs three times just to be sure.
多诺万调了半个城市的警察找你
Donovan's got half the force looking for you.
我们两人的东西
For the couple who has everything --
两部已连接的一次性手机
two matching burner phones.
当然卫星定位已经关了
GPS turned off, of course.
卡塞尔  我不能再让你继续陪着我了
Listen, Castle, I can't ask you to stick around anymore.
你不需要  我是自愿的
You don't have to ask. I'm volunteering.
不  这太危险了
No. It's too dangerous.
布莱肯现在知道了我是在唬他
Bracken knows that I was bluffing now --
他知道我没有那一堆对他不利的证据
that I don't have this huge file of evidence against him.
否则我就不需要为了扳倒他而去找瓦肯的麻烦
Cause if I did, I wouldn't have to go after Vulcan to bring him down.
我玩过火了
I've overplayed my hand.
现在已经没有什么能阻止他杀我了
There's nothing to stop him from killing me anymore,
他已经开始行动了
So he's making his move.
我也得做出回应
And I have to make mine.
我给他在华盛顿特区的办公室打了电话
I called his office in D.C.
布莱肯现在在纽约
Bracken's in New York.
那你的计划是什么
So, what's your plan?
你什么都没有就打算去找他吗
You're gonna take a run at him with nothing?
我还有什么选择
What's my other option --
躲起来等他们来逮捕我吗
hide in the shadows and wait for them to arrest me?
不出两天我就会被吊死在牢房里
Two days later, I'll end up hanging in my jail cell.
"前探长畏罪自杀"
"Rogue cop commits suicide."
也许还有别的办法
Maybe there's another way.
我从圣西蒙医院
I pulled the death certificate for Michael Smith
调出了迈克尔·史密斯的死亡证明
from St. Simon's Hospital.
是由奥利弗·普莱辛医生签署的
It was signed by a Dr. Oliver Pressing.
他是个合法医生  无不良记录
He's a legit doctor in good standing.
真是完美的人选
Someone above reproach --
假造死亡的绝佳人选
An excellent candidate to help you fake your death.
普莱辛医生和史密斯之间
Did you find any other connections
有什么联系吗
between Dr. Pressing and Smith?
事
As --
事实上  大有关系
As a matter of fact, I did.
普莱辛医生
Dr. Pressing?
纽约警局  我们有几个问题要问你
NYPD. We need to ask you a few questions.
我时间不多  我正要开始巡病
I don't have much time. I'm about to start my rounds.
我们了解到你是麦哲伦游艇俱乐部的一员
We understand you belong to the Magellan Yacht Club.
事实上  你是董事会成员之一
As a matter of fact, you are a member of the board.
俱乐部那边有什么问题吗
Well, is there a problem at the club?
你认识迈克尔·史密斯吗
Do you know Michael Smith?
你应该会认识他
It seems that you would,
因为他也是董事会成员
since he was also a board member.
我和史密斯先生是老相识  直到他去世
Well, I was acquainted with Mr. Smith, until he passed away.
抱歉  我有点糊涂了
Excuse me -- I'm a little confused.
你们问询的目的到底是什么
What's the nature of your inquiry?
我们正在找他
We're looking for him.
正如我说的  他已经不在了
Well, like I told you, he's deceased.
医生  是你帮他消失的
Doctor, you helped him disappear.
太荒谬了
That's absurd.
他死了我才签署了他的死亡证明
I signed his death certificate because he was dead.
求你了  我们只想联系上他
Please -- we just need to reach him.
我们知道他就在城里
We know that he's in town.
你帮他是因为你知道他处境危险
You helped him because you knew that he was in danger,
我们现在也四面楚歌
and we're in the same danger now.
非常抱歉
I'm sorry.
你在浪费你我的时间
You're wasting your time and mine.
医生  我们很会制造麻烦的
Doctor, we can make a lot more noise.
这是你想要的吗  这是他想要的
Is that what you want? Is that what he wants?
卡塞尔  我们得走了
Castle, we got to go.
我的照片不应该出现在新闻上
My picture shouldn't be on the news --
不会因为这个  也不会这么快的
Not for this, not this fast.
-布莱肯  -是的
- Bracken? - Yeah.
我们得快点出去
We got to get the hell out of here.
卡塞尔  走楼梯
Castle, stairwell.
等等
Wait.
是我的手机  那个一次性手机
It's my phone -- my burner phone.
怎么会有人
How did someone --
我不知道
I have no idea.
你好
Hello?
我知道你在找我  卡塞尔先生
I understand you're looking for me, Mr. Castle.
20分钟后老地方见
Meet me in the usual place -- 20 minutes.
是史密斯
That's Smith.
我们走
Let's go.
他迟到了
He's late.
也许他改变主意了或者害怕了
Maybe he changed his mind or got spooked.
这家伙从来不会怕
This guy doesn't spook.
你真的觉得他能帮我们
Do you really think he can help us?
他曾经帮过
He has before.
这个距离就够了
That's close enough.
我费尽心机才让自己活下来
I've gone to great lengths to keep alive.
现在我也得处处小心
I'd like to stay that way.
但你还是回来了
And yet, you came back.
我可以生活在阴影中
Well, I can survive in the shadows.
可我无法忍受终日不见阳光
I just don't want to live there forever.
你想扳倒布莱肯  我们也是
You need to take Bracken down -- same as we do.
总有办法的
There has to be a way.
是的  我以为我找到了
Yes, and I thought I'd found it.
我曾找到布莱肯的手下
I got to one of Bracken's men.
他告诉我还有一件让参议员
He told me there was something
非常害怕的证据
that the senator was afraid of --
是他以前的同伙为了自保录下来的
A recording made by a former associate to protect himself.
录音里布莱肯承认他曾谋杀
A recording in which Bracken admits to murder.
你知道录音在哪里吗
Do you know where it is?
不  布莱肯也不知道
No, and neither does Bracken.
尽管我和他一样花费了大量精力
Though he spent considerable resources
试图找到录音
trying to recover it -- as did I --
一年多了  都没有结果
for over a year, with no luck.
天呐  也许根本就不存在吧
Hell, it may not even exist.
但在我的搜寻过程中  我联系上了
But in my search, I did make a contact --
一个布莱肯组织里的顾问
A consultant in Bracken's organization --
他承诺他会曝光
And he promised that he could expose
布莱肯竞选融资涉及腐败
Bracken's campaign finances as corrupt.
可他也因此被杀了
But it got him killed.
杰森·马科斯
Jason Marks.
是的
Yes.
我很快就要说服他加入我们了
I was close to bringing him into the fold,
一定是被他们发现了
but they must have found out,
他也成了他们的累赘
which made him a liability.
一定还有其他办法扳倒布莱肯
There's got to be another way to get to Bracken.
没有了
There isn't.
我得从头再来
I just have to start again.
我们一直在调查瓦肯的犯罪网
We've been tracking Vulcan's network.
也许我们能帮上忙
Maybe we can help.
警探  你现在是泥菩萨过河
Detective, you are radioactive.
自身难保
You can't even help yourself.
不要再试图联系我了
Don't try to contact me again.
史密斯
Smith.
一定还有什么我们可以做的
There must be something we can do.
逃跑
Run.
消失
Disappear.
因为假如你们不走
Because if you don't...
他就会杀了你们
He will kill you.
新闻上都在说她
She's all over the news.
你有她的消息吗  电话  短信
You heard anything from them -- calls, texts?
从今天下午之后就没消息了
Not since this afternoon.
不知道他们的行踪  我们也不能妄动
And we can't make a move till we know where they are.
两位
Gentlemen?
是不是还有我不知道的内情
Is there something going on here that I should know about?
你是指什么
What do you mean?
贝克特不是杀人犯  这我知道
Beckett's not a killer. I know that.
但这个案子会毁了她
But she's gonna go down for this.
板上钉钉的事了  除非我能施以援手
It's open and shut, unless I can protect her.
但如果我蒙在鼓里  我没法保护她
And I can't do that if I'm left in the dark.
所以如果有人陷害她  我得知道原因
So if she's being set up, I need to know why.
长官  贝克特母亲被杀的案子你知道多少
Sir, how much do you know about Beckett's mother's murder?
就是普通的街头劫杀  是个悬案
It's a random stabbing -- never solved.
背后其实大有内情
There's a lot more to it than that.
跟我仔细说说
Tell me everything.
"逃犯"套房
The "fugitive" suite --
现金免登记能要到的最好房间了
best room that cash and no I.D. can buy.
我们必须反击布莱肯
We got to take the fight to Bracken.
找那盘没人找得到的神秘磁带吗
By looking for a mythical tape that no one can find?
史密斯说得对
No, Smith was right.
乔装之后  我们得赶紧逃走
Once we change your look, we get out of town.
卡塞尔  我妈妈常说
You know, Castle, my mom had a saying,
"唯真必胜"
"Vincit omnia veritas."
"真理战胜一切"
"Truth conquers all."
逃走的话我们就不能找到真相了
We'll never find the truth if we run away.
凯特  如果丢了性命  也找不到真相
Kate, we're never gonna find the truth if we're dead.
我们这不是逃避  而是保存实力  明白吗
We're not running away. We are surviving, okay?
为了能战斗到明天
We're living to fight another day.
我们一定会扳倒布莱肯
We will take down Bracken.
但首先我们得找到藏身之所
First, we're gonna find a safe place
然后想办法反击
and come up with a plan.
我认识一个人
I got a friend.
能不说二话就给我们搞到一辆车
He will give us a car, no questions asked.
那好  去吧
Okay. Go.
我会回来的
I'll be back.
我们会杀回来的
We'll be back.
卡塞尔
Castle?
你好啊  探长
Hello, Detective.
想都别想
Don't even think about it.
把剪子扔了
Drop the scissors.
我们本来说好了的  停火休战
We had an agreement -- a truce.
相安无事
"Live and let live."
我遵守了我的承诺  我甚至救了你一命
I held up my end of the bargain. I even saved your life.
这就能弥补你从我这夺走的东西了吗
And that makes up for what you took from me?
你怎么不想想我给了你的
What about what I gave to you?
你如今的地位  你如今的成就
Everything you are, everything you've accomplished
都是拜我所赐
is because of me.
这样你杀了人就能心安理得了吗
Is that how you justify murder?
还说什么"这使你成了更好的人"
"It builds character?"
为什么不给我个机会让你变得更好些
Then why don't you give me a chance to build yours?
你本来前景无限
You had a future.
你为什么就不能放下这些宿怨
Why couldn't you just let this go
好好过你的日子  让我也能向前看
and move on so I could do the same?
看来我今天说不动你
So, I guess there's no point
投我一票了  是不是
in asking for your vote, is there?
你参选不了
You're not gonna be on the ballot.
你的竞选资金来自贩毒
A presidential campaign financed by drug money
为了遮掩事实还连杀数人
with a trail of dead bodies?
这么猛的料你是埋不了的
There's no hole big enough to bury all of that.
实话跟你说
I got to tell you...
我真是有点钦佩你  你坚定不移的道德观
part of me really admires you -- your moral certitude,
为了信仰而战的劲头和手段
the way you fight for what you believe in,
即便明知会自毁前程也在所不惜
even knowing it's gonna destroy you.
但我的这点钦佩之心
But the part of me that admires you
可没法帮我作艰难的决定
is not the part that makes tough decisions.
那好
Fine.
杀了我
Then kill me.
动手吧
Do it.
朝我开枪吧
Pull the trigger.
我有专人代劳
I have people for that.
我不想让他们下手
I don't want them.
我想让你动手
I want you.
快动手吧
Do it -- now.
难道你没种亲自动手
Or don't you have the balls?
这样就会有证据把我和凶案现场联系起来
And create physical evidence linking me to the crime scene?
你明知道我没这么傻
We both know I'm smarter than that.
再见了  凯特
Goodbye, Kate.
真相一定会大白于天下的
The truth is gonna come out!
没有真相了
There is no truth.
不再有了
Not anymore.
不
No!
把她嘴撬开
Open her mouth.
那个胶囊是做什么用的
What was in that pill?
让你消停一会儿
Something to relax you.
现在我们得灌醉你
Now we're gonna take a little drink.
有证据能证明布莱肯犯下这些案子吗
Is there any proof that Bracken did these things?
现在没了
Not anymore.
蒙哥马利保存了一些文件  但现在也没有了
Montgomery had a file, but it's gone now.
长官  我们得帮她
Sir, we need to help her.
没有证据
No evidence...
对方又是权势熏天的政界大佬
Against one of the most powerful men in the country?
我们无能为力了
I don't think we can.
把枪拿来  她醉了
Get the gun. She's wasted.
别紧张
Relax.
就快完了
It's almost over.
把你的手指放进来
Let's get your finger in there.
很好
Good.
凯特
Kate?
他告诉我还有一件让参议员
He told me there was something out there
非常害怕的证据
the Senator was afraid of --
是他以前的同伙为了自保录下来的
A recording made by a former associate to protect...
录音里布莱肯承认他曾谋杀
...A recording in which bracken admits to murder.
当你走进第12分局时
When you walked into the 12th,
我感觉到了上帝之手
I felt the hand of god.
我知道他在给我另一个机会  然后我想
I knew he was giving me another chance, and I thought,
"如果我能像保护她那样的保护你"
"If I could protect you the way I should have protected her"...
你是蒙哥马利  蒙哥马利警监
You're Montgomery -- I mean, captain Montgomery.
我认识你吗  警官
Do I know you, officer...
贝克特
Beckett?
不  长官  我只是...我希望与您共事
No, sir. I just -- I've always wanted to do what you do.
我很想加入凶杀组
I wanted to be in homicide.
是吗  那你现在在哪个组
Is that right? What are you doing now?
巡逻组
Patrol.
这个我看出来了  我是问你在档案室里干什么
I see that. But what are you doing in the archives?
对不起  长官  我不是故意闯进来的
I'm sorry, sir. I didn't -- I didn't mean to be here.
我知道我不该来  但我在调查一个案子
I know I shouldn't be, but I was looking into a case --
我妈妈的谋杀案
My mom's homicide.
乔安娜·贝克特
Johanna Beckett.
你认识她吗
Did you know her?
我知道她的案子没破
I know her case is unsolved.
而你在查阅文件
And you're reviewing the files
看看他们是否漏掉了什么线索
to see if they might have... missed something.
是的
Yes, sir.
如果案子没破  很有可能
If the case is unsolved, chances are,
你要找的答案并不在这个文件里
the answers you're looking for probably aren't in that file.
你妈妈是做什么的  贝克特警官
What did your mother do, officer Beckett?
她是一名律师
She was a lawyer.
你觉得她的死或许和
You think her death might have had
她当时正在打的官司有关系吗
something to do with a case she was handling?
调查她的案子的警官
Well, the detective that was working her case --
拉格兰说这只是随机杀人  但是...
Raglan -- said that it was just random, but --
你有查阅她的私人用品吗
Well, did you look through her personal belongings --
旧的笔记本  账本  日记  磁带
Old notebooks, journals, diaries, cassette recordings --
之类的东西
stuff like that?
是的  看过很多遍了
Yes, sir -- tons of times.
但我还没找到任何与案件有关的东西
But I haven't found anything that seems relevant.
继续找吧
Well, keep looking.
或许哪天你会发现线索
You never know where something might turn up.
很高兴认识你  贝克特警官
Nice meeting you,Officer Beckett.
对于你妈妈的事  我很遗憾
Sorry about your mom.
谢谢  长官
Thank you, sir.
你感觉怎么样了
How are you feeling?
我们在哪儿
Where are we?
雷谱敦  佛蒙特州
Ripton, Vermont -- population 588.
过几个小时  我们就会到加拿大了
In a couple of short hours, we will be crossing into Canada.
调头
Turn around.
我们要回去
We have to go back.
什么
What?
是蒙哥马利
It was Montgomery.
是他把布莱肯那事录下来了
He made that recording of Bracken --
史密斯一直在找的那盘磁带是他录的
the one that Smith has been looking for.
蒙哥马利警监  你怎么知道的
Captain Montgomery? How can you possibly know that?
卡塞尔  当我第一次见到他的时候
Castle, when I first met him,
他说了些关于我妈妈谋杀案的事情
he was saying things about my mother's murder,
当时我没有明白过来
things that I-I didn't understand at the time.
但他特别提到了一盘磁带
But he specifically mentioned a cassette recording.
史密斯说过把那一切都录下来的人
And Smith said that the person who made that recording
是布莱肯的前同事
was a former associate of Bracken's.
没错  这下就都说得通了
Yeah. It adds up.
但如果蒙哥马利手里真的有那样的证据
Okay, but if Montgomery did have that kind of evidence,
他为什么不直接给史密斯呢
why wouldn't he have just given it to Smith?
我觉得他给我妈妈了
I think he gave it to my mom.
他问当我查阅她的东西时
He asked if I had been through her belongings,
是否发现了一盘磁带
if I came across a cassette.
凯特  如果他把磁带给你妈妈了  你肯定会发现
Kate, if he gave her the tape, you would've found it.
你查阅她的东西能有上百万遍了
You've been through her things a million times.
卡塞尔  我当时不知道该找什么
Castle, I didn't know what I was looking for.
答案就在那里  我知道
The answer is there. I know it.
在我公寓里有一大箱我妈的东西
I have a box of her things in my apartment.
我们要回去
We've got to go back.
你疯了吗  他们正监视着你家
That's crazy. They'll be staking out your place.
布莱肯不会派人去的  至少不是现在
Not Bracken's guys -- not now.
那多诺万的手下呢  他会派警察去守着的
And how about Donovan's guys? He'll have cops up there.
我们根本不可能靠近得了你家
There's no way we're getting near that place.
我们会进去的
We will.
我们只是需要一点帮助
We just need a little help.
各位  今天你们走运了
Hey, guys. Yeah, it's your, uh, luck day.
多诺万派我们来接班好让你们去吃点东西
Donovan sent us over so you can grab a bite to eat.
还有一个小时才到我们的午餐时间
We're not supposed to take lunch for another hour.
对不起  你现在不方便吗
Oh. I'm sorry. Is this not a good time for you?
要我们在这儿等着你们变饿吗
So, what? We should just wait here until you guys get hungry?
好吧  我们去吃点东西  马上回来
All right. We'll grab a slice and be back in a few.
谢了
Thanks.
你们有两分钟
You've got about two minutes.
如果蒙哥马利把磁带给她了
Okay, if Montgomery gave her the tape,
她肯定会对此做些笔记
she would have written something down about it.
我留了些她的笔记本放这箱子里了
I kept some of her notebooks in here.
该死
Damn it.
她的预约本
Her appointment book.
这是什么  某种速记吗
What is this -- some kind of shorthand?
是的  她在法学院时发明了一种代码
Uh, yeah, she developed a code when she was in law school
以防有人传唤她交出笔记
in case anyone subpoenaed her notes.
这方法太天才了
That's ingenious.
但弊端就是除了她没人知道那是什么意思
Except she was the only one who knew what it meant.
我把它交给我在国安局
I gave it to contacts
联调局和军情局的熟人
in the NSA, the FBI, military intelligence.
没有人破译出来了
No one was able to decipher it.
她就是在这天被杀了
This is the day she died.
这里面肯定写着些跟案子有关的事情
There's got to be something in here about that case.
我们可没时间查明了
Yeah, well, we don't have time to figure it out.
别看了  卡塞尔  我们要走了
Come on, Castle. We got to go.
看看这最后一条  "D.Me和家人"
Hey, look at this last entry -- "D. Me w/ family"?
"和家人吃晚餐"  她那天正是在
"Dinner with family" -- she was on her way
晚上去饭店找我们的路上被杀的
to the restaurant to meet us the night that she was killed.
看看"D"和"M"之间靠多近啊
Look how close the "D" is to the "M."
D.M.
"D.M."
蒙哥马利警监
"Detective Montgomery."
证据
"E" -- "Evidence."
蒙哥马利警监的物证
"Detective Montgomery evidence."
-难道你认为  -我是这样想的
- Do you think that --  - I do.
给家人
"With family."
你妈妈打算把带子拿给你们
She was bringing the tape to you --
也许为了安全  想把带子给你爸爸保管
Maybe to give it to your father for safekeeping.
那就是说她被杀时  证据在她手上
Which means she would have had it on her when she was killed.
布莱肯理应拿到那盘带子的
Bracken would've recovered that.
但我们知道他没有
Only, we know he didn't.
不然他也不会一直在找它
Otherwise, he wouldn't still be looking for it.
我妈妈把带子放哪了
So, what did she do with the tape?
很抱歉  兄弟们
Look, guys, I'm so sorry.
别这样  是我们弄砸了
Please. We're the ones who screwed up.
是我们让他们发现了你的行踪
We led them right to you.
看着他们俩  直到我回来
Keep them here till I get back.
我想亲自押送他们
I want to personally escort them to booking.
-卡塞尔  -别道歉
- Castle -- - Shhhh.
不是你的错
It's not your fault.
我以为我们能够成功的
I really thought we were gonna make it.
听着  不论发生什么事
Hey, whatever happens...
卡塞尔
Castle.
那个大象摆设
The elephants.
怎么了  我不太明白
I don't understand.
是我妈妈的
They were my mom's.
在我拿来摆在我桌上前  我妈妈一直放在她那
Before they were on my desk, she used to keep them on hers.
她过去一直说  它们就像我们一家人一样
She used to joke about how they were like a family,
我  我妈妈还有我爸
Just like us -- me, my mom, my dad.
它们是一家人
They were a family.
站着别动
Hey! Man, stay right there!
贝克特警探
Detective Beckett!
往后退  警探
Step back, Detective!
把它放下
Do it now!
-举起你的手  - 等等
- Show me your hands! - Wait!
把它放下
Put it down!
放下它  现在
Drop it! Now!
拉格兰  关上门
Raglan, shut the door.
你们三个跑到这儿胆子不小
You three got a lot of balls coming here.
-那是  -是布莱肯参议员
- Is that ...? - Senator Bracken--
他那时候是助理检察官
Back when he was still assistant D.A.
听着  我们只想确认
Look, we just
我们的想法一致
want to make sure we're all on the same page.
那是蒙哥马利的声音
And that's montgomery.
布莱肯  你可收了我们不少钱
You took us for a lot of money, Bracken.
我们想要万无一失
We want assurances.
我没起诉你们三个暗地里
Hey, be happy I haven't busted the three of you
勒索黑手党的事很给面子了
for your little mafia extortion ring.
别紧张
Whoa. Relax.
不不  你想要担保  给你
No, no. You want assurances? Here you go.
既然我能轻易把鲍勃·阿曼的死
I assure you that as easily
扣在普嘉迪头上
as I pinned Bob Armen's murder on Pulgatti,
我同样也能毫不费力地扣在
I could just as easily put it
真正杀人的的条子头上
on the cops who actually did the deed.
布莱肯承认了勒索他们
Bracken just admitted to blackmailing them.
对
He sure did.
普嘉迪知道他是被陷害的
Pulgatti knows he's been framed.
要是有人发现这事怎么办
What if someone gets onto this?
我会处理的
Then I'll handle them.
就凭你   你要怎么处理
You? How?
我人脉很广  罗伊  认识狠角色
I know people, Roy -- dangerous people.
不管是谁像那个贱人律师
Anyone gets too close -- like that bitch lawyer
乔安娜·贝克特那样查东查西
Johanna Beckett, who's been poking around --
我会让他们永远闭嘴
I'll have them killed.
雇凶杀人我干过
I've had people killed before.
参议员  你为什么想当总统
Senator, why do you want to be president?
这问题很简单  琳达
Well, it's simple, Linda.
我厌烦了那些地下交易
I'm tired of the backroom deals,
贪污腐败
the corruption, the waste.
老实说  我心累了
I'm exhausted, frankly,
我知道美国人民跟我一样
and I know the American people are, too.
听着  这个国家需要一个领导人  不会
Look, this country deserves a leader who won't ba--
不会
Who --
不会再在抗争中退缩
W-w-who won't fight -- who won't back down from a fight,
并曾为特殊群体谋福利
who has a-a proven...record
为他们的特殊需求而有所作为
of taking on the special interests
并且坚信
and, uh, believes
政府依然是社会向善发展的正面力量的人
that government can still be a force for good.
这些就是
These are the --
抱歉  我不得不终止这个采访
I-I'm sorry. I'm -- I'm -- I'm gonna have to cut this short.
参议员  有什么问题吗
Senator, is everything okay?
你不可能
You can't...
你不可能出现在这
You can't be here.
我发现那盘磁带了
I found the tape.
我找到它了
I found it.
一切都结束了
It's over.
布莱肯议员
Senator Bracken,
现在我们以涉嫌同谋诈骗
You are under arrest for conspiracy, fraud...
谋杀我的母亲乔安娜·贝克特的罪名逮捕你
...and the murder of my mother, Johanna Beckett.
请转身
Turn around, please.
我们接手吧
We'll take it from here.
布莱肯  我们等这一刻很久了
It's been a long time coming, Bracken.
她会以你为傲的
She's proud of you.
不管她身处何处  她都会因你而骄傲
Wherever she is, she's proud.
如果没有你  我不可能做到的
I never could have done this without you.